<rss version="2.0"><channel><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog/</link><title>Garden Reflections</title><description>A blog by Jeremy Nelson</description><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02024/06-01.html</link><pubDate>02024-06-01</pubDate><title>Red Dwarf Jade Plant</title><description><h1>Red Dwarf Jade Plant</h1>
<p>A few weeks ago I purchased on sale a <em>Crassula ovata</em> or "Crosby's Dwarf",
commonly called a Red Dwarf Jade Plant (not be confused by the enjoyable 
British classic television show <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Dwarf">Red Dwarf</a>).</p>
<p>My wife and step-daughter purchased a pot for the Red Dwarf Jade Plant and on Saturday
I re-potted the Jade Plant into it's new pot:</p>
<p><img alt="Red Dwarf Pre-Potting" src="img/02024-06-01_red-dwarf-pre-repotting.png" /></p>
<p>Here is the Red Dwarf Jade in it's new pot:</p>
<p><img alt="Red Dwarf new pot" src="img/02024-06-01_red-dwarf-new-pot.png" /></p>
<p>We decided that our front entrance, that has a small table and two chairs, would be
the best place to put the new Red Dwarf Jade Plant:</p>
<p><img alt="Red Dwarf Jade Plant front steps" src="img/02024-06-01_red-dwarf-location.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02024/05-09.html</link><pubDate>02024-05-09</pubDate><title>Measuring and Watering Lemon Tree and Salvia Amistad</title><description><h1>Measuring and Watering Lemon Tree and Salvia Amistad</h1>
<p>I am writing this blog post on my new iPad's Github App.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago my wife purchsed this <em>Salvia Amistad</em> to attract
hummingbirds to our patio. Pictured below:</p>
<p><img alt="Salvia Amistad" src="img/02024-05-09-salvia-amistad.png" /></p>
<p>One of the features of the iPad is that it's camera can
be used to measure objects. I tried using it on the 
lemon tree:</p>
<p><img alt="Limon Tree measures" src="img/02024-05-09-lemon-tree.png" /></p>
<p>The weather has been great the past couple of days so I'm
working on my patio garden for the summer. I will post
another blog post on Saturday.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02024/03-23.html</link><pubDate>02024-03-23</pubDate><title>Beginning of Lemons?</title><description><h1>Beginning of Lemons?</h1>
<p>This weekend I continue to prune flowers from the lemon tree (seen below)</p>
<p><img alt="Lemon Tree" src="img/02024-03-23_lemon-tree.png" /></p>
<p>I noticed on some of the flowers that had lost their petals, a small 
yellow bud that I believe are the beginnings of the lemon fruits.</p>
<p>Here is one of the nascent fruits:
<img alt="Fruit and flowers for Lemons" src="img/02024-03-23_lemons-flowers-01.png" /></p>
<p>In this photo, you can see all of the phases of the lemon flowers; 
from the flower bud, to the flower, to two of the beginning lemons:
<img alt="Detail of Lemon flowers with starting fruits" src="img/02024-03-23_lemons-flowers-02.png" /></p>
<p>One of the great things about gardening is that this question will be answered as 
time passes and will resolve the hypothesis as evidence comes in (i.e. Lemon or not) </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02024/03-17.html</link><pubDate>02024-03-17</pubDate><title>Replanting Dracaena and Lemon Tree</title><description><h1>Replanting Dracaena and Lemon Tree</h1>
<p>It has been over six months since I wrote in this blog. I have 
found less garden-related material since we moved to Pacifica and
our townhome's back patio doesn't have any soil for plants. However,
over the weekend I re-potted a sick <a href="https://www.apartmenttherapy.com/dracaena-plants-our-best-tips-for-growing-and-care-240389">Dracaena</a> 
into a new pot, changing out the soil because we believe one of the
pets when we lived back in Colorado Springs had urinated on the tree.
My lemon tree was still in the yellow plastic pot from the store so 
I decided to clean and re-use the Dracaena's pot and replant the Dracaena
in a new pot. This photo is the work-in-progress (and I actually feel 
like a gardener!):</p>
<p><img alt="Soil from replanting the Dracaena with the Lemon Tree" src="img/02024-03-17_dracaena-lemon-tree-prep.png" /></p>
<p>Here is the cleaned pot prior to re-planting the lemon tree:</p>
<p><img alt="Cleaned Pot for Lemon Tree" src="img/02024-03-17-lemon-tree-new-pot.png" /></p>
<p>After finishing transplanting Dracaena's new pot:</p>
<p><img alt="New pot for Dracaena Plant" src="img/02024-03-17-draceana-new-pot.png" /></p>
<p>And finally, the new Lemon Tree in it's new pot (along with it's old pot)!</p>
<p><img alt="Lemon Tree's old and new pots" src="img/02024-03-17-lemon-tree-new-and-old-pots.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02023/07-24.html</link><pubDate>02023-07-24</pubDate><title>San Pedro Hike</title><description><h1>San Pedro Hike</h1>
<p>Where we live in Pacifica allows for a short walk to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Pedro_Valley_County_Park">San Pedro Park</a>.
Yesterday, I walked the <a href="https://www.smcgov.org/parks/trail/old-trout-farm-loop-trail">Old Trout Farm Trail</a> and 
took the following photographs of the massive Tasmanian blue gum (<em>Eucalyptus globulus</em>) trees that surround the trail.</p>
<p><img alt="Old Trout Farm Trail San Pedro Valley Park" src="img/02023-07-23_old-trout-farm-trail.png" /></p>
<p>Also present are Redwoods pines and a lot of ferns in the undergrowth. </p>
<p><img alt="Redwood On Old Trout Farm Trail" src="img/02023-07-23_redwood_san_pedro_park.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/12-19.html</link><pubDate>02022-12-19</pubDate><title>Pacifica in December</title><description><h1>Pacifica in December</h1>
<p>With this being my first winter in Pacifica, I've observed a couple of things related
to my ongoing gardening efforts (or lack thereof). The first is that although it never
freezes (or hasn't yet) it still is cold at night with temperatures dropping into the 30s or
40s Fahrenheit. This past weekend we experienced sun but the previous couple of weeks we had
rain every day. My sprouts are doing well with the moisture but I do need to clean the containers
and keep emptying the bottom container. I also earlier in the month planted the remains of celery
stalk and that seems to be doing well.</p>
<p><img alt="Celery Stalk growing in pot" src="img/02022-12-19-celery-mung-bean.png" /></p>
<p>I've also been looking at the <a href="https://cesanmateo.ucanr.edu/?calendar=yes&amp;g=72662">classes</a> 
available at the local UC Extension office after reading an off-hand comment made in a 
recent <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2022/12/who-gains-and-loses-from-the-new-ai.html?utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=who-gains-and-loses-from-the-new-ai">blog post</a> by Tyler Cowen on recent advances in LLM and in particular 
<a href="https://openai.com/blog/chatgpt/">ChatGPT</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Currently the bots are much better at writing than say becoming a master gardener, which also 
requires skills of physical execution and moving in open space. We might thus see a great 
blossoming of talent in the area of gardening, and other hard to copy inputs, if 
only to protect one's reputation and IP from the bots.
- Tyler Cowen <em><a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2022/12/who-gains-and-loses-from-the-new-ai.html?utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=who-gains-and-loses-from-the-new-ai">Who gains and loses from the new AI?</a></em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>While my gardening talent and skills are at best marginal (bad pun), I am interested in improving
and learning more about how I can become better at both. Given that my space now is limited to a 
concrete slab and indoor plants, I feel like volunteering a community garden as part of certification
process for a master gardener would be a good step (although reading about the requirements for the
master gardener certification including background checks, seems a bit arduous).</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/11-19.html</link><pubDate>02022-11-19</pubDate><title>New Mung Bean Sprouts</title><description><h1>New Mung Bean Sprouts</h1>
<p>Due to the rain we've had, the small sprout grower is actually growing
sprouts in the various trays in the grow container! I snipped a few
of the Mung Bean and Wheatgrass sprouts and after washing them, had a 
nice fresh little bite.</p>
<p><img alt="Mung Bean Sprouts" src="img/02022-11-19-mung-bean-sprouts.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/10-22.html</link><pubDate>02022-10-22</pubDate><title>Pacifica Walk</title><description><h1>Pacifica Walk</h1>
<p>Living in a townhome community in Pacifica that borders running water, direct from my
front-door a private sidewalk follows the stream through the complex. I took the
following photos as an interested gardener. </p>
<p><img alt="Mushroom on Stump" src="img/02022-10-22_mushroom-log-stump.png" /></p>
<p>I am hoping these mushrooms are <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laetiporus_sulphureus">Laetiporus sulphureus</a></em> but they are communal resource and a very a real risk of being poisonous. </p>
<p>One of my neighbor has a large and aspiration citrus container tree:
<img alt="Citrus Hybrid Container Tree" src="img/02022-10-22_citrus_container_tree.png" /></p>
<p>My next plant purchase is going to be a citrus container tree of my own.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/09-22.html</link><pubDate>02022-09-22</pubDate><title>A Pacifica First - Prepping the Sprouts Tray</title><description><h1>A Pacifica First - Prepping the Sprouts Tray</h1>
<p>I am no longer living in Colorado! My house, the principle 
place as a subject for this blog is to be sold on October 5th.
I definitely have mixed feelings &#9785; but I am so 
excited to be living less than 2 miles from Pacifica 
State Beach!!</p>
<p>We are renting a town-home with a concrete deck bordered
by 8 foot-tall wooden fence. Because of import restrictions,
I gave away my lemon tree (origin Florida) and other plants 
so I am definitely starting anew with a total container 
garden. One of the many great things living in this 
surprising sunny microclimate, is that I'll be able to 
garden year-around! </p>
<p>Expect more blog posts (and back fill the last posts from 
Colorado. </p>
<p>Attached to the patio is a small laundry room that I'm 
also using for my art projects and gardening supplies. 
Inspired by one my favorite writers, <a href="https://om.co/about/">Om Malik</a>,
recent blog post <a href="https://om.co/2022/09/16/why-and-how-of-blogging/">Why (and how) of blogging</a>,
he quotes and links to Robin Rendle's 
<a href="https://www.robinrendle.com/notes/take-care-of-your-blog-/">Take Care of Your Blog</a>,
I'll continue writing and posting my photos and videos.</p>
<p>Tonight, I unpacked my sprouts grower appliance and 
prepped it with seeds while on the dryer, and put 
my first grow bed outside on the patio.</p>
<p>Here is the set-up:</p>
<p><img alt="Mung Bean, Wheatgrass, and Peas" src="img/020220922_grow-station-prep.png" /></p>
<ul>
<li>Mung Bean</li>
<li>Wheatgrass</li>
<li>Peas</li>
</ul></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/05-21.html</link><pubDate>02022-05-21</pubDate><title>Snow in May</title><description><h1>Snow in May</h1>
<p>I took the following photo of our back-yard patio after today's 
late May snow-storm. </p>
<p><img alt="Snow in the backyard" src="img/02022-05-21_snow-in-backyard.png" /></p>
<p>As typical of Colorado Springs weather, the
previous weeks was beautiful with the false-promise of Spring. We
need the moisture and I had to go to both the front and back to 
shake snow out of the trees otherwise they were at risk of breaking.
My neighbor had significant damage to the pine tree in their 
front-yard. Most of the trees in Colorado Springs were planted after
the town was founded in the late 1800s by General Palmer. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/05-18.html</link><pubDate>02022-05-18</pubDate><title>Lavender and Bees</title><description><h1>Lavender and Bees</h1>
<p>As has been my habit over the past couple of years, I captured the following
bees pollinating the lavender bushes in the front yard. Wait until the end
for a surprise visitor!</p>
<video controls="" height="480" width="640">
<source src="vid/020220518_lavender-bees.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/04-08.html</link><pubDate>02022-04-08</pubDate><title>Removal of Beds, prep for this Summer</title><description><h1>Removal of Beds, prep for this Summer</h1>
<p>My family and I are moving to the San Francisco Bay area this 
summer and my focus for gardening and landscaping efforts is
on selling my house. Today I took off from work and tore out 
the front-yard mentioned <a href="#2020/09-26">here</a>, <a href="#2020/05-07">here</a>,
<a href="#2020/03-23">here</a> in 02020 and <a href="#2019/06-07">here</a>, <a href="#2019/08-28">here</a>
in 02019.</p>
<p>The front-yard before:</p>
<p><img alt="Front yard flower beds" src="img/02022-04-09_flower-beds.png" /></p>
<p>Here is cleaned front-yard with the flower beds removed and the cleaned 
up bushes:</p>
<p><img alt="Front yard" src="img/02022-04-09_front-yard.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02022/01-09.html</link><pubDate>02022-01-09</pubDate><title>Lemon Tree and a New Year</title><description><h1>Lemon Tree and a New Year</h1>
<p>The new year brought mild temperatures during the day while still getting 
cold at night. We did have one snow storm last week in Colorado Springs 
with snow patches still remaining in the shade. The lemon tree (more like a 
lemon shrub) sole lemon approches full ripe so I'll be picking it soon. </p>
<p><img alt="Lemon on the Lemon Shrub" src="img/02022-01-09_lemon-tree.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/10-05.html</link><pubDate>02021-10-05</pubDate><title>Fall/Failing Garden</title><description><h1>Fall/Failing Garden</h1>
<p>Here is a photo I took of the frost-hit cherry tomato plant in a container:</p>
<p><img alt="Cactus and Dying Tomatoes" src="img/02021-10-05_cactus-and-tomatoes.png" />:</p>
<p>As you can see, I failed to harvest the remaining tomatoes, which symbolizes
my lack of effort on my garden over the summer. I didn't water the onion beds
enough (you can't just garden over the weekends) with the resulting failure of
any harvest-able onions. I'll just leave the blubs over the winter and hopefully
in the spring, I'll do better job in 2022.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/08-29.html</link><pubDate>02021-08-29</pubDate><title>Seed bombs on the Back Hill</title><description><h1>Seed bombs on the Back Hill</h1>
<p>My wife attended an environmental workshop at her employer and the 
participants were given "seed bombs" of native grasses and
flowers. We decided to plant them in the Rose Bed/Onion Bed
as the onions have wilted and died over the hot summer days 
with little mosture. Here is the seed bomb after we watered:</p>
<p><img alt="Seed Bomb Planted and Watered" src="img/02021-08-29_seed-bombs.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/08-28.html</link><pubDate>02021-08-28</pubDate><title>Mowing the Front Yard</title><description><h1>Mowing the Front Yard</h1>
<p>Even though the late summer has been hot and dry, the front yard
lawn continues to grow, especially the weeds and other non-grass
plants. I have been negligent in watering the front (and truth 
be told in the back onion-and-rose bed as well) but I decided
to mow the front yard, it looks better now.</p>
<p><img alt="Front yard mowed" src="img/02021-08-28_mowed-front-yard.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/07-28.html</link><pubDate>02021-07-28</pubDate><title>Roses with Unexpected Guest</title><description><h1>Roses with Unexpected Guest</h1>
<p>I took the following photo of the blooming rose along with 
a couple of other rose buds close to blooming. </p>
<p><img alt="Roses with Insect" src="img/02021-07-28_roses-in-rose-bed.png" /></p>
<p>When I looked at the image closely, I noticed that maybe
a pincer beetle was also enjoying the fresh scent (or 
more likely the pollen) of the main rose.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/07-12.html</link><pubDate>02021-07-12</pubDate><title>Deer in the Neighborhood</title><description><h1>Deer in the Neighborhood</h1>
<p>Walking this afternoon, I noticed this Whitetail deer in a near-by neighbor's yard.
We have deer roam our neighborhood often but I liked the velvet covered new antlers 
of this particular buck. </p>
<p><img alt="Buck in the Neighborhood" src="img/02021-07-12_buck-in-the-neighborhood.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/06-13.html</link><pubDate>02021-06-13</pubDate><title>Bees in the Lavender Flowers</title><description><h1>Bees in the Lavender Flowers</h1>
<p>Short of pattern (i.e. on the way to becoming a habit and then tradition), I captured
the bees in our lavender bushes out front.</p>
<video controls="" height="480" width="640">
<source src="vid/020210613_bees-lavender.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/06-10.html</link><pubDate>02021-06-10</pubDate><title>First Cherry Tomato of the Season</title><description><h1>First Cherry Tomato of the Season</h1>
<p>In my back-yard container garden, I harvest the first ripe (or nearly ripe) cherry tomato
of the season. Just after picking this one:</p>
<p><img alt="Picking this tomato" src="img/02021-06_cherry-tomato.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/05-29.html</link><pubDate>02021-05-29</pubDate><title>Stir-fry with Onion Greens</title><description><h1>Stir-fry with Onion Greens</h1>
<p>Augmenting Chinese take-out from the night before, I added kale, mushrooms, 
and carrots and began cooking them in my small wok. As I didn't have any 
onions available, I went outside and clipped some green stalks from the 
growing onions in the back onion bed. Here they are before chopping:</p>
<p><img alt="Onion Greens on Cutting Board" src="img/02021-05-29_green-onion-stalks.png" /></p>
<p>Here is the wok cooking with all of the vegetables:</p>
<p><img alt="Wok with Vegetables" src="img/02021-05-29_wok-with-vegs.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/05-22.html</link><pubDate>02021-05-22</pubDate><title>Weeding Onion Beds (and a photo-bomb by Teddy)</title><description><h1>Weeding Onion Beds (and a photo-bomb by Teddy)</h1>
<p>The onions are growing well over the past couple of weeks
with almost daily rain showers. The onions aren't the only
growth with the weeds starting to fill in the gaps and even
in some cases displacing the young onions. As I was finishing
up and taking a picture, our new kitten, Teddy, decided to
hunt grasshoppers and you can see him about to lunge in 
the upper right of this photo:</p>
<p><img alt="Onions with Teddy" src="img/020210522_onions-and-teddy.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/05-01.html</link><pubDate>02021-05-01</pubDate><title>Mayday Planting Onions, Tomato, and Peppers</title><description><h1>Mayday Planting Onions, Tomato, and Peppers</h1>
<p>Today being the first of May and in solitary and celebration with all of the workers in the
world that make our lives possible, I decided to finish planting the onions in the Rose
beds. Early afternoon I went to my favorite Garden Center, <a href="https://www.goodearthgardencenter.com/">Good Earth</a>, and purchased two seedlings bundles of Walla Walla onions and planted them 
among the roses and the art we have in the back beds:</p>
<p><img alt="Roses, Art, and new Onion Seedlings" src="img/02021-05-01_roses-art-onions.png" /></p>
<p>At <a href="https://www.goodearthgardencenter.com/">Good Earth</a> I also purchased a Fantastico cherry tomato plant for the container 
and two pepper plants I put into a pot you can see on the side:</p>
<p><img alt="Cherry Tomato and Peppers Containers" src="img/02021-05-01_cherry-tomato-peppers.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/04-25.html</link><pubDate>02021-04-25</pubDate><title>Onion Bed Planting</title><description><h1>Onion Bed Planting</h1>
<p>This afternoon I planted the onion bulbs I had picked up a few weeks ago,
here is the bulb packet:</p>
<p><img alt="Onion Bulb Packet" src="img/02021-04-25-onion-bulbs.png" /> </p>
<p>The package claimed that there were 100 bulbs, I didn't count them but 
I did plant the entire packet with each build about 4 inches from each
other. The onions were planted in back roses bed which did have some
leftover bulbs growing from previous years already.</p>
<p><img alt="Rose and Onion Beds" src="img/02021-04-25-onion-beds.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/03-06.html</link><pubDate>02021-03-06</pubDate><title>Planting Strawberries</title><description><h1>Planting Strawberries</h1>
<p>A few days ago I was at a big box store had onions and strawberries starter
bulbs and plants and I picked a bag of each. Although the weather is in 
60s today here in Colorado, I am going to hold off on planting them until
later this month. However, I decided I'm going to plan one of the strawberry
plants in a pot just to see if I can get it started.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/02-28.html</link><pubDate>02021-02-28</pubDate><title>Lemon Tree pH Test</title><description><h1>Lemon Tree pH Test</h1>
<p>A few months (or even a year or more), I purchased an analog pH testing
probe that I've been meaning to start testing the soil for any of the 
container or potted plants. Today I decided to test the soil for the
Lemon Tree and I looked up via an internet search, the ideal range of 
a potted lemon tree is between 5.5 and 6.5 pH. Testing the soil, I 
took a picture here:</p>
<p><img alt="Lemon with pH Sensor" src="img/02021-02-28_lemon-ph-test.png" /></p>
<p>Looking at the gauge, the soil is close to being neutral at 7, so
I will look at adding a fertilizer to make the soil slightly more
acidic. Left over from my stepdaughter's science project, I decided to
use some mulch to make a layer in the Lemon tree because the roots are 
slightly showing and provide some protection and water retention. I
am hoping that the lemon tree will flower again as it warms up and having
extra nutrients available should help. </p>
<p>Next weekend my wife and I will harvest the lemon for some 
celebratory gin and tonics.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/02-21.html</link><pubDate>02021-02-21</pubDate><title>Visiting Ricks and Starting New Sprouts</title><description><h1>Visiting Ricks and Starting New Sprouts</h1>
<p>Yesterday I stopped by <a href="https://www.ricksgarden.com/">Rick's Garden Center</a> just down 
the street from my house. My stepdaughter is doing a science project for her high 
school class and needed some mulch for one of her experiments. While I was there, 
I picked up three sprouting seed packets:</p>
<ul>
<li>Alfalfa Seeds</li>
<li>Mung Bean</li>
<li>Wheatgrass</li>
</ul>
<p>I then cleaned the residuals sprouts and seeds from the sprout growing trays and
I intend to start a new bunch of spouts tomorrow. I will also create two new
seed bottles as I have the extra bottles.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/01-30.html</link><pubDate>02021-01-30</pubDate><title>Lemon and Sprout Harvest with new Seeds</title><description><h1>Lemon and Sprout Harvest with new Seeds</h1>
<p>Almost at the end of January and although the weather varies between nice and 
snow, a single lemon from my <a href="#2020/12-16">Lemon</a> tree is about ready to be picked. </p>
<p><img alt="Lemon on the Lemon Tree" src="img/02021-01-30_lemon-tree-lemon.png" /></p>
<p>I've already eaten the Alfalfa sprouts and I'm about to harvest the remaining along 
with the red clover sprouts. I have started recycling my plastic prescription 
bottles to store my seeds. Part of the conceit for my Bug-out Library is that will
have a seed library. As these bottles become available, I cut-out the paper seed
package and paste/glue the label to the bottles. Here are the latest:</p>
<p><img alt="Seed Bottles" src="img/02021-01-31-seed-bottles.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02021/01-09.html</link><pubDate>02021-01-09</pubDate><title>Sprouts Starting in the New Year</title><description><h1>Sprouts Starting in the New Year</h1>
<p>Today's snow started earlier in the day and continues. Before I left for Aikido 
class, I went out to the garage, picked up the sprouts trays from the garden grow 
hub, and watered them in the kitchen sink. Since I started back to work last Monday,
I haven't been able to record the watering like I was intending in the
Jupyter notebook but both the Alfalfa and the Red Clover seeds started sprouting.</p>
<p>The garage isn't heated and so the growth of the sprouts are stunted; however,
I think the next purchase for the garden grow hub will be a heating mat. I took
the following photo from the top and you can see the Alfalfa seeds starting to 
sprout.</p>
<p><img alt="Seed Sprouting" src="img/02021-01-09_alfalfa-sprouts.png" /></p>
<p>The grow of new life (even with these sprouts) is an appropriate as I start the next
year of my life.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/12-26.html</link><pubDate>02020-12-26</pubDate><title>Seed Sprouter Notebook and Data</title><description><h1>Seed Sprouter Notebook and Data</h1>
<p>I started the over-night soak for both Red Clover and Alfalfa seeds that
I'll transfer to the first layer in the Seed Sprouter I purchased earlier
in the week. I started a <a href="https://github.com/jermnelson/garden-blog/blob/main/nb/seed-sprouter.ipynb">Jupyter notebook</a> to manage the <a href="js/seed-sprouter.json">data</a> 
I'm collecting to track the full-growth cycle for sprouting seeds to harvesting 
for two different seeds. My plan is to start the second layer after the 
first of the year.  </p>
<p>Here is the current set-up for the seeds being soaked in the Garden Grow
hub:</p>
<p><img alt="Seeds on overnight soak" src="img/02020-12-26_seeds-sprouter-soak.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/12-22.html</link><pubDate>02020-12-22</pubDate><title>Garage Gardening Hub</title><description><h1>Garage Gardening Hub</h1>
<p>Two new additions to the my garage indoor growing hub, mentioned
<a href="#2200/06-07">earlier</a> this year. Today shopping for
holiday gifts at my favorite gardening nursery, <a href="https://www.goodearthgardencenter.com/">Good Earth</a>,
I purchased a Seed Sprouter along with Red Clover and Alfalfa seeds to 
start growing sprouts in the upcoming year. More to come. </p>
<p><img alt="Indoor Garden Hub" src="img/02020-12-22_garden-hub.png" /></p>
<p>A few weeks ago I purchased a Landscape Drip watering system, 
seen at the bottom of the above photo. Using minimal parts from the entire
kit, by the beginning of 02021, I'll be able to water any plant growth
in the upper shelf of the hub. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/12-16.html</link><pubDate>02020-12-16</pubDate><title>Lemon Tree Flowering</title><description><h1>Lemon Tree Flowering</h1>
<p>The container lemon tree started flowering again even though there
is still one unripened lemon on the tree from the last (and only)
harvest. This time I'll try to keep more than one lemon resulting
from these flowers. The weather in Colorado Springs is cold with 
some sporadic snow that makes gardening during warmer times seem
like a pleasant dream.</p>
<p>Here is the best cluster of flowers from the lemon tree. Notice in the top-left corner,
a leaf that some insect snacked from this summer when the lemon tree was outside:</p>
<p><img alt="Lemon flowers" src="img/02020-12-16_lemon-tree-flowers.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/11-07.html</link><pubDate>02020-11-07</pubDate><title>Raking Leaves and Pruning Lavender</title><description><h1>Raking Leaves and Pruning Lavender</h1>
<p>With projected rain and snow in the forecast, I decided to do some yard
work in the front starting with raking the leaves and removing
the dead lavender stalks from the plants. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/10-18.html</link><pubDate>02020-10-18</pubDate><title>Container Garden Moving Indoors</title><description><h1>Container Garden Moving Indoors</h1>
<p>The temperature in Colorado Springs definitely dropping over the past few days. 
Friday night my wife and I moved the temperate container plants indoors with 
the lemon tree moving underneath the existing coffee table growing station.</p>
<p><img alt="Lemon Tree under House Plant Grow Station" src="img/020201018_lemon-tree-house-plants.png" /></p>
<p>The Denver Bronco's win coupled with progress on various local art projects makes today
enjoyable despite the cold weather, the continuing Covid-19 pandemic, and the unusually
stress of 2020 elections. My garage growing station needs improvement to grow any winter 
fresh vegetables. At least improve the frequency of my winter blog posts!</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/09-26.html</link><pubDate>02020-09-26</pubDate><title>Maize Growing in Front Garden</title><description><h1>Maize Growing in Front Garden</h1>
<p>During the hot summer days of July, on a whim I planted some sweet maize (corn)
in the front yard and now at the end of September, it has grown about a foot
with no chance that will grow large enough to harvest any food. </p>
<p><img alt="Maize in Front Yeard" src="img/020200926_maize.png" /></p>
<p>This entire growing season has been a failure, with none of the celery, onions, lettuce,
or tomatoes maturing enough for any harvest (I take that back, I was able to harvest
some lettuce for hamburgers one evening)</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/09-07.html</link><pubDate>02020-09-07</pubDate><title>Preparing for First Freeze</title><description><h1>Preparing for First Freeze</h1>
<p>Right now the temperature is in the high eighties with the air dense 
from the wild fires in Colorado and beyond. The weather is forecast 
to drastically change overnight and into tomorrow with the low being
below freezing with snow and rain! I'll be bringing inside the container
garden for the night although I hope to move them back outside at 
lease until the end of the month and maybe into October.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/09-05.html</link><pubDate>02020-09-05</pubDate><title>Weeding with Hari Hari</title><description><h1>Weeding with Hari Hari</h1>
<p>Using my new hari hari Japanese gardening knife (actually made in China), I weeded
the front-yard's stone beds. I love the point and handling of the hari hari and
when I came across this black and orange spider, I took the following photo with
the blade:</p>
<p><img alt="Spider with Hari Hari" src="img/020200905_spider-hari-hari.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/08-28.html</link><pubDate>02020-08-28</pubDate><title>Repotting House Tree</title><description><h1>Repotting House Tree</h1>
<p>My brother Jacob gave my wife and I for our wedding a tree house-plant that
is now part of my container garden. I've been remiss and although I 
purchased a nice pot a couple of years for the plant, up until today I 
just kept in it's original black plastic container. Here is the tree
plant (please <a href="mailto:jermnelson@gmail.com">email</a> if you know the name)
in it's new ceramic pot:</p>
<p><img alt="Tree Plant" src="img/020200828_tree-house-plant.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/08-08.html</link><pubDate>02020-08-08</pubDate><title>Prickly Pear Cactus and Silver Sage</title><description><h1>Prickly Pear Cactus and Silver Sage</h1>
<p>A large lot north on 19th has been abandoned for a while with an 
established forest. I think the lot has been sold along with the 
adjacent house so I wanted to save at least a couple of plants 
before it is developed into houses, condos, or apartments (best
scenario). </p>
<p>This morning I took my new Chinese-made <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hori_hori">Hori hori</a>
and three black cast-off soil containers to put two Prickly Pear or 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opuntia"><em>Opuntia</em></a> plants along with a nearby
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_cana">sunflower</a> or <em>Artemisia cana</em>. </p>
<p>This is photo is when I was digging out the first prickly pear (the Artemsisia cana
was only a meter or two away) with the Hori hori with it's orange handle
stuck in the ground.</p>
<p><img alt="Digging out the prickly pear" src="img/020200808_digging-prickly-pear.png" /></p>
<p>I quickly discovered that my gloves didn't protect my hands from the very tiny
spines and for the reminder of the day I have removing the spines with tweezers 
from my fingers. </p>
<p>When I got back to the house, I discover one of the two prickly pear cactus had 
white film on the underside that looked like bird guano but I don't think it was.
I first planted the <em>Artemsisa cana</em> in it's own pot and my wife took a photo 
of me at around that time below:</p>
<p><img alt="Plant the silver sagebunch" src="img/020200808_planting-silver-sagebrush.png" /></p>
<p>After finishing planting both the cactus and the silver sagebrush, I made a short 
video of my container garden, with my lemon tree, my new plants, and the seasonal 
cabbage and tomato plant:</p>
<video controls="" height="480" width="640">
<source src="vid/02020808_container-garden.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/08-01.html</link><pubDate>02020-08-01</pubDate><title>Lemon Tree First Yellow Fruit and Rosemary Bush</title><description><h1>Lemon Tree First Yellow Fruit and Rosemary Bush</h1>
<p>This morning when practicing Tai Chi on the back patio, I looked over 
to the lemon tree and saw this beautiful sight:</p>
<p><img alt="Lemons on the Tree" src="img/020200801_lemons-on-tree.png" /></p>
<p>Of the four lemons, the first turning yellow is one of the smallest. I
am excited that one of my favorite plants is producing fruit. For the first
year, the four fruit are exciting to see. </p>
<p>I dropped off Carmen at her work and on the way back I stopped off at my 
favorite garden center, <a href="https://www.goodearthgardencenter.com/">Good Earth</a> and
purchased a couple of pots for a project I'm starting and I also was able to 
purchase a small Rosemary plant below:</p>
<p><img alt="Rosemary Plant" src="img/020200801-rosemary.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/07-18.html</link><pubDate>02020-07-18</pubDate><title>Celery Garden Scrap Transplant</title><description><h1>Celery Garden Scrap Transplant</h1>
<p>This is my third or forth attempt and growing out from the stalk of celery
a new transplant. The previous attempts all failed with the celery transplants 
dying when I planted them in the back-yard onions and roses bed. This time 
I am taking a different approach and planting the celery transplant in the
the front-yard next to the flower beds. </p>
<p><img alt="Front-yard Celery Transplant" src="img/02020-07-18_celery.png" /></p>
<p>I hope with the full sun and watering, that this attempt will be more successful
than my past attempts. I will also grow another celery transplant from my next
store purchase of celery stalks for the family meals. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/07-03.html</link><pubDate>02020-07-03</pubDate><title>Stella d'Oro</title><description><h1>Stella d'Oro</h1>
<p>In the front-yard flower bed closest to the street, the mystery flower has 
finally bloomed with a couple of bright yellow flowers. My wife 
texted my mother-in-law with a photo who identified the plant as a 
<a href="http://www.perennials.com/plants/hemerocallis-stella-de-oro.html">Stella d'Oro</a> 
or yellow day lily.</p>
<p>The rain this afternoon and early evening is beaded on the leaves in this 
photo of the Stella d'Oro:</p>
<p><img alt="Stella d'Oro Day Lilly" src="img/020200703_stella-d-oro.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/06-13.html</link><pubDate>02020-06-13</pubDate><title>Tomato, Lettuce, and Red Cabbage</title><description><h1>Tomato, Lettuce, and Red Cabbage</h1>
<p>I went to the <a href="http://phelangardens.com/">Phelan Gardens</a> after 
Aikido class today (our first since March) where we practiced 
social distancing Aiki warm-up and 7-bokken suburi. Before 
and after class we washed the mat with a water-bleach solutions. 
I purchased a tomato, four red cabbage, and a lettuce selection. 
The tomato and two of the red cabbages I planted in the cherry
tomato container from last year. The lettuce and two of the 
red cabbages I planted in the container.</p>
<p>Here is a photo of new tomato plant:</p>
<p><img alt="New Tomato and Red Cabbage Container" src="img/020200613_tomato-red-cabbage.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/06-07.html</link><pubDate>02020-06-07</pubDate><title>Structural Onions, Lemon Tree, and other Additions</title><description><h1>Structural Onions, Lemon Tree, and other Additions</h1>
<p>For the past few months I've growing out celery stalks from the leftover
marketplace celery I base a lot of my cooking savory meals around especially
during the Covid-19 self-isolation and restaurants closures these past 
few months. My first attempt grew out and then died back finally shriveling
up and dying when transplanted into the orange rectangular container. </p>
<p>My second celery attempt started a couple of weeks ago and is to the (healthy) I
hope the new celery stalk is ready for replanting in the backyard's Onions 
and Roses bed. The celery stalk is in a small glass jar seen between the legs of
easel (currently my third painting in the Floyd's Dreams of Dylan painting
and pirate radio <a href="https://github.com/jermnelson/floyds-dreams-of-dylan">series</a> in the photo below of my garage biological grow hub and 
my oil painting studio:</p>
<p><img alt="Grow Hub and Painting Studio" src="img/020200607_grow-hub-and-art-easel.png" /></p>
<h2>Bamboo Structural Support for Onions</h2>
<p>With the onions in their second year, a couple of these have recently been
flattened by human or other means. In one of the kitchen drawers, we have 
bamboo skewers that I repurposed into structural supports for these fallen
onions tied with kite string as seen in this photo:</p>
<p><img alt="Onion with Bamboo Supports" src="img/020200607_onion-bamboo-structural-support.png" /></p>
<h2>Horizontal Art, Lemon Tree, Roses, Onions, and Celery</h2>
<p>With both my wife and I working from home we both frequently look out into the
back-yard and so now in the bed we have our ceramic art fetish, my lemon tree (moved 
outdoors for the summer from inside the house), the newly supported onion, followed with 
the orange and green steel cactus art, with another onion and newly planted celery 
plant, all pictured from left-to-right in this photo from today:</p>
<p><img alt="Art, Lemon Tree, Onions and Celery" src="img/020200607_art-lemon-tree-roses-onion-celery.png" />`</p>
<p>I just love how both the front have improved tremendously under my wife and step-daughters
efforts over the past couple of months. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/05-22.html</link><pubDate>02020-05-22</pubDate><title>Butterflies and Bees</title><description><h1>Butterflies and Bees</h1>
<p>The lavender bushes in the front-yard are starting to bloom with 
butterflies and bees busy pollinating as seen in this video I 
took today:</p>
<video controls="" height="480" width="640">
<source src="vid/020200522_butterfly-bee-lavender.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video>
<p>This is inspiring to see and a welcome sight. I've decided I'll be joining my 
wife for a 30 minute daily gardening session starting next Tuesday. I hope 
that my writing output on this blog will increasing accordingly for the 
2020 summer of the Covid-19 pandemic.  </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/05-07.html</link><pubDate>02020-05-07</pubDate><title>Front Flower Beds</title><description><h1>Front Flower Beds</h1>
<p>My wife and step-daughters stopped by <a href="http://www.ricksgarden.com/">Rick's Garden Center</a>
last night and picked up an assortment of flowers and bushes for the 
two flower beds in the front-yard. In each of the beds there is a 
Little Turdy Catmint (<em>Nepta psfike</em>) and a Gold Star Potentillas (<em>Potentilla fruticosa</em>)
plants. Tonight I planted both of the beds. In the Southern most flower bed that closet to
street and receives the most sun, we planted a Rocket City Daylily <em>Hemerocallis</em> 
and Ruby Stella <em>Hemerocallis</em>. In between these bushes we planted clusters of Ocean Breeze
and Harvest Mix Violoas:</p>
<p><img alt="Southern Front-yard Flower Bed" src="img/020200507_front-flower-bed-01.png" /></p>
<p>After I planted the second Catmint plant with the purple flowers, two 
bumblebees almost immediately came and started feeding which you can see
in this photo:</p>
<p><img alt="Two Bumblebee under Catmint" src="img/020200507_bumblebees.png" /></p>
<p>Here is that bed with a new Plantain Lily Hosta that reminds me of Illinois.</p>
<p><img alt="Northern Front-year Flower Bed" src="img/020200507_Northern-flower-bed.png" /></p>
<p>In all an unexpected but wonderful mid-week gardening opportunity on this 
fine Colorado Spring evening.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/05-02.html</link><pubDate>02020-05-02</pubDate><title>Weeding the Front and Back Yards</title><description><h1>Weeding the Front and Back Yards</h1>
<p>My wife is doing her <a href="https://www.uww.edu/cobe/doctorate">DBA</a> program from 
home this weekend due to the Covid-19 pandemic instead of traveling to Whitewater, 
Wisconsin this weekend. In the morning I weeded the dandelions in the front yard 
and noticed that the 
lavender bushes are starting to bud and should be flowering soon. In the picture
below you can see at the corner of the sidewalk there is my basket of weeds 
next to a new sage bush growing between lavender </p>
<p><img alt="Front-yard Lavender and Sage Bushes" src="img/020200502_sage-lavender-corner.png" /></p>
<p>In the backyard, I weeded the entire Onions and Roses bed and took this photo
showing the onions, roses, the Fetish Art Drop, and two steel flower decorations
that is pictured here:</p>
<p><img alt="Onions, Roses, and Art bed" src="img/020200502_onions-roses-art-bed.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/04-30.html</link><pubDate>02020-04-30</pubDate><title>Watering the Onions and Roses</title><description><h1>Watering the Onions and Roses</h1>
<p>Late this afternoon-to-early-evening, I decided to water the onion beds and
roses as the ground is getting dryer (not unrelated to the current emerging
<a href="https://www-washingtonpost-com.stanford.idm.oclc.org/weather/2020/04/16/southwest-megadrought-climate-change/">megadrought</a>) 
here in Colorado. In the picture below, you can see the art work, the line of onions with 
sprayed water.</p>
<p><img alt="Onion and Roses Bed with Fetish Art" src="img/020200430_onion-roses-art.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/04-19.html</link><pubDate>02020-04-19</pubDate><title>Yard work and weeding</title><description><h1>Yard work and weeding</h1>
<p>This weekend my wife, step-daughters, and I worked in both the front and 
backyards cleaning, picking weeds, and general yard chores on Saturday
and Sunday. The weather was nice both mornings with increasing cloudy 
weather starting in the afternoon. My wife focused on the clipping the 
dead grasses back to the green growth. She then used our electric leaf blower 
for the first time and blew out the leaves in our front-yard rock beds and 
the bushes into the street and our driveway. My stepdaughters Meghan and 
Carmen swept up the leaves, dirt, and dust into our trash can. On Sunday,
they both picked up rocks as we started cleaning some of the rock beds in
the back yard.</p>
<p>I picked dandelions in the front yard and I kept and cleaned the young 
dandelion greens for an early spring salad that I had for a late lunch today. 
I also added some of the microgreens that were close to the correct size 
from my indoor grow station. There a few more seeds starting to come up and
I hoping with the forecasted warmer weather for the next week that I'll have
more seeds sprouting. I am going to wait until the second or third of week
of May before relocating the seeds into the rose beds or into their separate 
outdoor containers for the upcoming season. I had started growing a celery 
stalk from <a href="https://www.apieceofrainbow.com/veggetables-herbs-regrow-kitchen-scraps/">kitchen scraps</a>
and I'll probably move it to a garden container first or take the plunge and 
plant it in the roses and onion beds. One good note is that onions continue
to grow from last season and as long as we continue to water it when dry, 
I am hoping for a mid-summer harvest of onions.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/04-05.html</link><pubDate>02020-04-05</pubDate><title>Installing Garden Art among the Roses</title><description><h1>Installing Garden Art among the Roses</h1>
<p>Today one my jobs was to install a piece of garden art I 
was able to pick for the Texas 2019 Christmas white elephant
gift exchange with my wife's family. Initially, I 
had installed the ceramic rain-drop inverted but after asking
my wife to confirm, I fixed and she took the following photo 
this afternoon:</p>
<p><img alt="Standing with newly installed Garden Art" src="img/020200406_jeremy_art_installed.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/03-23.html</link><pubDate>02020-03-23</pubDate><title>Cleaning up Lavender Beds</title><description><h1>Cleaning up Lavender Beds</h1>
<p>This morning I worked in the front yard cleaning up the lavender beds by removing
leaves and the old stems. Here is the yard before the clean-up (along with our black
cat Rocky crossing in the background): </p>
<p><img alt="Before Weeding/Cleanup" src="img/0202003-23_before-cleanup.png" /></p>
<p>Removing the dead stems and leaves took some time and even then there still needs to be
another round of leave clean-up as seen in this after photo:</p>
<p><img alt="After Weeding/Cleanup" src="img/020200323_after-cleanup.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/03-16.html</link><pubDate>02020-03-16</pubDate><title>Seed Grow Station</title><description><h1>Seed Grow Station</h1>
<p>After being inspired last <a href="#2020/03-12">Thursday</a>, I started my indoors seed starting
station and went ahead and created three of the egg carton seed packs. I also planted
a micro-greens pot and in another pot planted one of the onion bulbs from last year. 
Some of the last year's seed pods were re-hydrated and planted some of the remaining
beans and squash seeds.  </p>
<p>In the photo below, the egg carton seed cartons in the black trey are from front to the
back:</p>
<ul>
<li>The three sisters - corn, green beans, and zucchini</li>
<li>Tomatoes from the super successful cherry tomato plant from last season and pumpkin
    seeds from last fall, and some beets seeds from Ann Grant Martin</li>
<li>Arugula, Kale, and Spinach</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="Seed Grow Station" src="img/020200316_grow-station.png" /></p>
<p>The two brown bottles hold water and in the lower-left corner there is a couple of 
my paint brushes (my easel is adjunct to the grow station) are in jar with paint thinner.
Because of the COVID-19 virus imposed social distancing, all of my family is staying at
home. Being able to start on the cultivating seedlings for this season's garden provides
a much needed balance and connection to the larger reality beyond the fear of the 
ongoing pandemic. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/03-12.html</link><pubDate>02020-03-12</pubDate><title>Onions in Early March</title><description><h1>Onions in Early March</h1>
<p>Last fall I didn't harvest very many onions that were the Rose bed because most 
of them have died or so I assumed from the lack of green tips. Last week I 
noticed as the weather in Colorado Springs has improved, that some of those
abandoned onions are sprouting back up with the most prominent pictured 
below:</p>
<p><img alt="Onion Sprout" src="img/020200312_onion.png" /></p>
<p>Last weekend I put on my todo list to start the seedlings for planting this
spring and I always seem to have an excuse. I need to get the light fixed and
most of the first two trays planted, perferrable this afternoon. This year
I am using cardboard egg cartons for containers to hold the seeds. The added
advantage is that I can use a pen to mark what is where.</p>
<p>My immediate goal is the create a three-sisters planting on a single six-egg
carton and then tranport them to the very successful cherry tomato planter from
the last year. I am curious to see if the container is too constraining for the corn 
or if all three plants (the other two being beans and squash) can survive as a well.</p>
<p>It would be nice if I could cultivate the three-sisters in this manner.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/02-13.html</link><pubDate>02020-02-13</pubDate><title>Re-potting the Lemon Tree</title><description><h1>Re-potting the Lemon Tree</h1>
<p>I think the size of the pot for my new lemon tree was too small and too much of the
root crown was exposed. I had an extra plastic container that moved the lemon tree 
into that does a better job of covering the roots and gives the tree more room to grown.
In the small window of sun shine during the 20 degree Fahrenheit day, I replanted and
took this photo (I wish it was warm as it looks, the sun in Colorado is always deceptive 
during the winter)</p>
<p><img alt="Lemon Tree" src="img/20200213_lemon-tree.png" /></p>
<p>The bottom of the lemon tree's container has a reservoir to store extra water so I hope 
that will help reduce the occurrence of all of the soil being dried up that was part of
the issue with the smaller terracotta pot.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02020/01-15.html</link><pubDate>02020-01-15</pubDate><title>California Dreaming</title><description><h1>California Dreaming</h1>
<p>For my first blog post of 2020 (and it being winter here in Colorado Springs) I 
decided to replant a lemon tree I purchased late last year into it's own pot. </p>
<p><img alt="Lemon Tree" src="img/20200115_lemon-tree.png" /></p>
<p>When I am in Palo Alto, my cube on the Lanthrop third floor looks into a courtyard that 
contains lemons and kumquats in planters. When I was there last week, the lemons were
starting to ripen. These lemons are delicious and so inspired me to buy and try to keep
living my lemon tree. I did notice that the pot I picked is about the same size and 
container I purchased with the roots being container bound. I'll likely need to purchase 
a larger pot this summer.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/12-31.html</link><pubDate>02019-12-31</pubDate><title>Final Thoughts for 2019</title><description><h1>Final Thoughts for 2019</h1>
<p>As the last day of 2019, my garden adventures for the year are complete 
with very mixed results. I killed too many <a href="#2019/04-20">plants</a> and <a href="#2019/09-10">here</a>,
I failed in both planting <a href="#2019/05-03">seedlings</a> and from most of onions I planted int
the ground. My notable successes were with container plants, both onions and the
<a href="#2019/08-10">cherry tomato</a> plant. I did a lot of <a href="/#2019/08-04">weeding</a> and 
<a href="#2019/09-10">bush removals</a> along with other gardening work around the house. In all, 
even though most of my ambitions was folly, documenting my experiences in this blog 
and spending time gardening was a source of deep satisfaction and humbling of my 
initial hubris. </p>
<h2>2020 New Year Garden Resolutions</h2>
<p>Looking over the past year, here are my gardening goals for the new year:</p>
<ul>
<li>Start seedlings sooner, allow them to grow larger before planting in the
    ground and in containers</li>
<li>More of mix between in-ground plantings and container gardening</li>
<li>Plant less perennials</li>
<li>Start a drip irrigation system for at one of the new beds</li>
</ul></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/10-27.html</link><pubDate>02019-10-27</pubDate><title>Harvesting Container Onions</title><description><h1>Harvesting Container Onions</h1>
<p>The weather forecast for Colorado Springs is snow for the next couple 
of days so I decided to harvest three of the onions in the long 
container before the snow starts coming down. I picked the three
 and noticed although the size of the onions where not great, the
length of the roots was significant and think the long rectangular 
box was too shallow for the deep rooted onions for next season's
garden. Here are the three onions freshly picked with the rich soil 
still attached:</p>
<p><img alt="Three Onions before the snow storm" src="img/20191027_3-onions.png" /></p>
<p>After cleaning the onions, I decided to keep one of the larger onions
with the most roots out to plant in my internal winter garden in a
deeper pot but I chopped up the small onion and the other larger one in 
a pan with carrots that eventually became the base for the bean soup
for Sunday's dinner:</p>
<p><img alt="Carrots and Onion cooking" src="img/20191027_onions-carrots.png" /></p>
<p>This is after all the ultimate goal for my gardening efforts this year 
and for this blog was to at least to supplement the diet of myself and 
my family going into the winter.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/10-09.html</link><pubDate>02019-10-09</pubDate><title>Growing season Wind Down</title><description><h1>Growing season Wind Down</h1>
<p>The latest weather forecast for Colorado Springs calls for snow and drastically
reduced high temperature in 30s Fahrenheit. I decided to move the one remaining
tomato plant indoors and see if I can keep the plant alive as long as possible
in my portable grow station. This cherry tomato plant has been the most
productive plant in this season's garden adventures and it will be an interesting
experiment to see how long this plant lives indoors. I decided to hold off in 
harvesting the remaining onions in the rose bed and in the long container. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/09-22.html</link><pubDate>02019-09-22</pubDate><title>Back from Sweden; Tomatoes and Garden Center</title><description><h1>Back from Sweden; Tomatoes and Garden Center</h1>
<p>Last week I was in Stockholm at the National Library for a conference 
where I presented on two different panels related to my work as software
engineer. Before I left, I thought I gave instructions for watering
the cherry tomato plant that is now in the backyard. This morning I
harvested three tomatoes and picked up about five or six ripe tomatoes 
from the ground that I've moved indoors. I am going to try to get 
them to grow over the winter or at least be able to harvest the seeds
for next spring.</p>
<p>My favorite garden center sent me an email with a number of coupons
that have induced me to go there after the Denver Broncos game (an 
expected loss to Green Bay given how they've been suffering from three
turnovers and no sacks or takeaways). I purchased a stone pot to replant
a Ficus house plant my brother gave my and wife last summer for our
wedding. I like how it looks:</p>
<p><img alt="Ficus in new pot" src="img/20190922_ficus-new-pot.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/09-10.html</link><pubDate>02019-09-10</pubDate><title>Removing Cinquefoil Bushes and Digital Timer</title><description><h1>Removing Cinquefoil Bushes and Digital Timer</h1>
<p>A couple of days ago, after prompting from my wife, I went and finally 
removed the dried out Cinquefoil bushes we had planted earlier in the 
<a href="#2019/08-04">summer</a>. I noticed the root ball of all but one bush were
root bound and still in the same of the plastic pots they came in. My 
best guess is that we really need to water and continue to water any
new bushes or other plants we attempt on the hill next year. Here is an
example of the one of the smaller Cinquefoil bushes on the sidewalk:</p>
<p><img alt="Dead Cinquefoil" src="img/20190910_dead-cinquefoil.png" /></p>
<p>In a less depressing topic, I found doing a web search the manual for 
the Workchoice <a href="img/workchoice-wc2011-manual.pdf">WC2011 Digital Timer</a> 
that I used last winter and spring to grow the
three sister <a href="#2019/05-03">seedlings</a> that never grew when I replanted
them into the backyard onion and rose bed. Now that the weather is 
starting to get cooler, I want to start again and see if I can get a
small indoor garden space going again for fall, winter, and next 
spring. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/08-28.html</link><pubDate>02019-08-28</pubDate><title>Water and Tree Removal</title><description><h1>Water and Tree Removal</h1>
<p>I watered the front cherry tomato plant in the front
year this afternoon.</p>
<p><img alt="Cherry Tomato" src="img/20190828_tomato.png" /></p>
<p>Growing with the front bushes were two larger upshoots from 
tree stumps I had cut down in previous years.</p>
<div class="grid-two-columns">
<div>
<h4>Before</h4>
<img alt="Tree Saplings Before" src="img/20190828_tree-saplings.png" />
</div>
<div>
<h4>After</h4>
<img alt="Removed Tree Samplings" src="img/20190828_tree-saplings-removed.png" />
</div>
</div>
<p>Of course, since I haven't dug up these small stumps, next year I'll 
likely have to trim the saplings again in this location.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/08-26.html</link><pubDate>02019-08-26</pubDate><title /><description><h1>White-tail (<em>Odocoileus virgininus</em>) Life-cycle</h1>
<p>This afternoon I took Foxy, our chow mix, for a walk down our street and 
a young fawn was spooked out of one of the Northeast neighbor's yard and
stop to watch us. I took this photo of our encounter:</p>
<p><img alt="Fawn Closeup" src="img/20190826_fawn.png" /></p>
<p>The fawn bounded off with Foxy and I continue walking down the street.
We then broke off and followed a path through a still wild field where
as looked at these flowering bushes and grasses, I thought of how
it may look in my backyard hill after our disaster of planting 
this spring and summer. Here is the trail we were following:</p>
<p><img alt="Wild Plants" src="img/20190826_native-plants.png" /></p>
<p>As I was thinking about how with gardens we try to enforce  our values, 
our vision, onto the land, these flowering plants reflect a baseline
that I need to do a better job of observing and integrating into 
my labor in the yards of my house and community. I like that I don't
have a back fence along my properties and the hill is wild with often
visits from deer eating along the ridge. </p>
<p>Funny enough, when I got back home and went out back there was a 
magnificent buck resting at the top of my property line pictured 
in silhouette pictured here:</p>
<p><img alt="Buck resting" src="img/20190826_buck.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/08-18.html</link><pubDate>02019-08-18</pubDate><title>Watering Onions and Roses</title><description><h1>Watering Onions and Roses</h1>
<p>The past few days in Colorado Springs have been dry with hot days. 
Today I watered the onions in the backyard roses and onion bed:</p>
<p><img alt="Roses and Onions watered" src="img/20190818_onions-parsely.png" />
. 
I selectively watered the remaining onions using a plastic bucket.
As I went back and forth filling the bucket with house water,  I 
remembered reading the news reports
about <a href="https://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ofr20191048">It is raining plastic</a> about microplastics found in 90% of the samples of rain water in 
Denver and Boulder. I wonder how my practices in the garden, 
like using a plastic bucket for watering, are  contributing to 
microplastic pollution in Colorado Springs? </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/08-10.html</link><pubDate>02019-08-10</pubDate><title>Onions and Roses, Purple Fungus, and Cherry Tomatoes</title><description><h1>Onions and Roses, Purple Fungus, and Cherry Tomatoes</h1>
<p>When I got home from Aikido practice, I started weeding the back, 
in, what I got a little chuckle in the bad pun <em>Onions and Roses</em> rock band,<br />
main growing bed in the back-yard. As I was removing the morning glories vines
from the bed as they crowd out the onions, in the photo below you can
the row of onions are next to stone wall on the right with the roses on 
the left.</p>
<p><img alt="Row in the Onions and Roses Bed" src="img/20190810_onions-roses.png" /></p>
<p>When I was removing these vines, I thought of my role in the garden as the 
fitness function of these adaptive systems of grow plants. My intention in 
removing unwanted plants is improve the environment for the plants that I 
want to thrive and succeed. But, I was looking at these particular morning
glory vines and how resilient and tough these plants are, I wonder for the 
2020 growing season that I plant and start early climbing peas in the same 
areas and try to grow them as a replacement in the niche currently being 
exploited to great effect by these climbing vines.</p>
<h2>Purple Fungus</h2>
<p>Since 2013, my first spring and summer in this house, I have notices this
purple fungus on many of the weeds in both the front and back. On the
south side of the house (what I'm now going to start call Strawberry Row,
as the strawberry plants there are doing well) there was a particularly
bad patch I took the following photo of one plant with leaves in various
stages of infection:</p>
<p><img alt="Purple Fungus on Plant Leaves" src="img/20190810_purple-fungus-plant-leaves.png" /></p>
<p>I am not sure what this fungus does or is called but since it seems to only infect
(so far as I can tell) common weeds that I would have normally picked anyways). 
I was able figure it out in 5 minutes of web research but I'll continue to look 
into this. In the meantime, when I pick these infected weeds I'm isolating them
from my two compost bins and my plan is to burn them once they dry out.</p>
<h2>Cherry Tomatoes</h2>
<p>So my cherry tomato plant impulse buy started producing and ripening small tomatoes
that I have started picking and eating once ripe! here is a close shot of a ripe
tomato on that plant that I also took today:</p>
<p><img alt="Ripe Cherry tomato" src="img/20190810_cherry-tomato-closeup.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/08-04.html</link><pubDate>02019-08-04</pubDate><title>Removing Dead Bushes, Weeding, and Watering</title><description><h1>Removing Dead Bushes, Weeding, and Watering</h1>
<p>For the past couple of weeks I've either been out-of-town (last
week at this time I was finishing up a 5-day Aikido Summer Camp in 
the Rockies at <a href="http://boulderaikikai.org/">Boulder Aikikai</a>) or
haven't done much gardening other than weeding and watering the
onion bed and the new tomato plant. </p>
<p>The four bushes my wife purchased earlier in the summer are all dried
up and look died. I'm not sure if was the lack of watering initially
or for some other reason, one problem with the bushes location on the
backyard hill is that water retention isn't great. When I went up the
hill today to look at the four bushes, I noticed green leaves sprouting
on a couple of the branches in one of the bushes picture below.</p>
<p><img alt="Hillside Dry Shrub" src="img/20190804_dry-shrub.png" /></p>
<p>The next time we plant a bush or tree on the hill we should look at using <br />
drip irrigation to ensure a consistent supply of water. Disappointing
for sure. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/07-16.html</link><pubDate>02019-07-16</pubDate><title>Onion Bed Weeding and new Cherry Tomato Container</title><description><h1>Onion Bed Weeding and new Cherry Tomato Container</h1>
<p>During my lunch 1/2 hour today, I briefly went through and weeded the
onion bed in the back yard. Most of the weeds are off-shoots of the climbing
vine that has a mass of roots through-out the bed. I imagine as an underground
network spreading out and finding its way for any opportunity to burst 
through a weak spot or sunny location in the onion bed to send up a quick
growing shoot.</p>
<p>This weekend in a fit of consumer loss of will-power, I purchased a large 
cherry tomato plant within it's own container that I have put in the
front sidewalk, pictured here:</p>
<p><img alt="Cherry Tomato Container Plant" src="img/20190716_cherry-tomato.png" /> </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/07-02.html</link><pubDate>02019-07-02</pubDate><title>Red and Yellow Roses (on the same bush)</title><description><h1>Red and Yellow Roses (on the same bush)</h1>
<p>The second largest rose bush in the back garden
recently bloomed. In the past and up until recently,
all of the Roses in the back-yard were red. </p>
<p>A couple of days ago, a yellow rose appeared and 
here is photo of the usual red roses in the 
upper-left with the new yellow rose in the
lower right.</p>
<p><img alt="Red and Yellow Roses" src="img/20190702_roses-red-yellow.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/06-28.html</link><pubDate>02019-06-28</pubDate><title>Back from Trip &amp; Weeding</title><description><h1>Back from Trip &amp; Weeding</h1>
<p>Late Wednesday night I flew back to Denver and then took the shuttle
from DIA to the Antlers Hotel in Colorado Springs. Yesterday I spent
the day mostly in bed recovering from a summer chest cold (still not
100%) but today I was able to do some weeding in the onion bed. </p>
<p>Feeling the warmth and brightness of the sun on my face, I hope
when I'm recovering from a future illness I'll be able to garden
a bit. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/06-16.html</link><pubDate>02019-06-16</pubDate><title>Yew Bushes Trimming &amp; Bees in the Lavender</title><description><h1>Yew Bushes Trimming &amp; Bees in the Lavender</h1>
<p>This morning and afternoon started with picking weeds in
the both the backyard onion patch and in the lawn before I mowed.
I then shot the following video of bees and flies pollinating<br />
the lavender bushes in the front:</p>
<video controls="" height="480" width="640">
<source src="vid/bees-lavender.mp4" type="video/mp4" />
</video>
<p>Later in the afternoon, I went back to trimming a yew bushes in the
front. Under the bushes is a rock border that I wanted to reveal 
that was over-grown. I cut them back as seen in this photo:</p>
<p><img alt="Yew Bushes " src="img/20190616_yew-bushes.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/06-07.html</link><pubDate>02019-06-07</pubDate><title>Front-yard Flower Beds</title><description><h1>Front-yard Flower Beds</h1>
<p>Yesterday, my wife Melissa went to a large retail tool and garden center and purchased a
number of flowers for the front-yard. The red geraniums and yellow lilies really stand-out 
surrounded by the lavender bushes.</p>
<p><img alt="Front-yard Flower Beds" src="img/20190607_front-flower-garden.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/05-19.html</link><pubDate>02019-05-19</pubDate><title>Third "Three" Sisters Planting</title><description><h1>Third "Three" Sisters Planting</h1>
<p>None of the initial "three" sisters planting of corn, eggplant, and green beans came up
and since I have initial seedlings ready for planting, I decided to replant the 
available seedlings in the same location as the initial seedlings. I also and weeded
the front-yard and along the side of the house leading up to the <a href="#2019/05-14">second strawberry patch</a>.</p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/05-14.html</link><pubDate>02019-05-14</pubDate><title>Strawberry Patch Two</title><description><h1>Strawberry Patch Two</h1>
<p>Sunday I arrived back from a professional conference in Boston and
yesterday as I was looking at the first Strawberry patch on the 
enclosed side of the house, I noticed a ripe strawberry that I picked
and enjoyed just a taste of the hopefully, more to come in the
upcoming years. On the opposite side of the house is a 
second patch strawberry patch on side of the hill pictured below:</p>
<p><img alt="Second Strawberry Patch" src="img/20190514_strawberry-patch.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/05-03.html</link><pubDate>02019-05-03</pubDate><title>Second Sisters Planting</title><description><h1>Second Sisters Planting</h1>
<p>The weather this past week in Colorado Springs ranged from snow
to rain until today with the sun provided an opportunity to go outside and
engage the garden. </p>
<p>Earlier in the spring I started a seed starter grow station in my 
garage that provide the source seeds in my first foray into a three
sister's planting. Starting withe the seedlings with the most 
growth pictured here:</p>
<p><img alt="Seed Starter Grow Station" src="img/20190503_grow-station.png" /></p>
<p>A closer grouping of the seedlings to plant:</p>
<p><img alt="Sisters Seedlings" src="img/20190503_three-sisters-seedlings.png" /></p>
<p>Here are the seedlings near the final position in the garden 
patch before being planted this afternoon:</p>
<p><img alt="Sister seedlings in position" src="img/20190503_sisters-position.png" /></p>
<p>Here is the final planting using soil from the existing 
compost augmented with some dirt from a purchased bag of 
garden soil:</p>
<p><img alt="Sister Plants" src="img/20190503_sister-plants.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/04-28.html</link><pubDate>02019-04-28</pubDate><title>New Compost Bag, Onion and Roses Bed</title><description><h1>New Compost Bag, Onion and Roses Bed</h1>
<p>Yesterday I went to my new favorite <a href="https://www.goodearthgardencenter.com/">garden-center</a> and 
purchased a "<a href="https://smartpots.com/compostsak/">compost sak</a>" for the 
front yard. This morning I set-up the sack and placed next to the gate to the backyard
(see the photo below)
I picked up the remaining cuttings from my trimming the yew bushes in
the front as well as a round of weeding the front yard. </p>
<p><img alt="compost sak in front-yard" src="img/20190428_compost-sak.png" /></p>
<p>Later in the afternoon, I weeded and watered the onion and rose bed which you see
in the second photo below. Also, you can start to get a sense of the hill in the 
backyard as well. </p>
<p><img alt="Onion and Rose bed" src="img/20190428_onions-roses.png" /></p>
<p>I should confess that an important source of inspiration is watching through
Monty Don series on Netflix, with my wife and I watching the second episode in the
French gardens series. Today I first heard the French style of kitchen garden,
or portage, from the French word for soup, were herbs, fruits, vegetables, and 
flowers are all combined into an integrated whole with the focus on the vegetables.
Just a quick internet search turned up two articles, <em><a href="https://www.bbg.org/gardening/article/potager">Learn to How to Create a Potager: A French Kitchen Garden</a></em> and 
<em><a href="https://www.growveg.com/guides/how-to-design-a-potager-garden/">How to Design a Potager Garden</a></em>. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/04-23.html</link><pubDate>02019-04-23</pubDate><title>Weeding Dandelions</title><description><h1>Weeding Dandelions</h1>
<p>The rain of the past two days in Colorado Springs resulted in a
number of dandelions popping up in the front-yard. Between meetings
this afternoon, I picked a few and then took the first photo
of my weeding tools and bucket, along with the largest patch of these
"weeds". Most weeds I don't have any qualms about removing them from the
front lawn or in the various garden beds but I am ambivalent about dandelions
because, unlike many of the weeds, they are edible and I feel like instead of
composting them, I should clean and prep them for a meal. <br />
<img alt="tools and dandelions" src="img/20190423_dandelion.jpg" /></p>
<p>I also came across this multi-colored, that I believe is a
pansy that grew from seed as a part of last year's pansies in the front-yard beds.
<img alt="unknown flower" src="img/20190423_flower.jpg" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/04-21.html</link><pubDate>02019-04-21</pubDate><title>Berry Hedge Beginnings</title><description><h1>Berry Hedge Beginnings</h1>
<p>My stepdaughter Meghan and I planted a few weeks three berry bushes,
a red raspberry, a black raspberry, and a blackberry bushes at the
top of my Pike Peak's foothill backyard. As seen in the photo below,
I labeled each of the new bushes with an unique IRI built using the EFF's dice
word-list to generate random three-word phrases as names instead of me trying
to come up with new names and ids for the plants I want to track.</p>
<p><img alt="Berry Hedge" src="img/20190421_berry-hedge.png" /></p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author><item><link>https://jermnelson.github.io/garden-blog//02019/04-20.html</link><pubDate>02019-04-20</pubDate><title>Initial Garden Reflections</title><description><h1>Initial Garden Reflections</h1>
<p>Starting today, I write to reflect on today's work in my garden, 
located on the Westside of Colorado Springs. Most of my backyard is
the side of a foothill that with it's siblings, merges west into 
Pikes Peak. </p>
<p>My current work is in a rose garden that over the past years I've lived
here, I've routated between the roses, loosely-called compost pits. 
Finally this year, I'm actually planting both onions and 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Sisters_(agriculture)">three sisters</a>
of first nation origin. </p></description></item><author>jermnelson@gmail.com</author></channel></rss>